Guide to the Blatchford, Potter, and Delano Family Papers 1796-1995 (bulk, 1796-1919) MS 3132
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Delano family, 1895-1948
  - III.B. Susan Magoun (Adams) Delano (1848–1904)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1899 January-April (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1899 July-September (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1899 October-December (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1900 January-April (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1900 May-November (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1901 January-June (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1901 July-December (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Letters to son, William Adams Delano, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - III.C. William Adams Delano (1874–1960)
    Architect, in partnership with Chester Holmes Aldrich as Delano & Aldrich, designers in the Beaux-Arts tradition. Son of Eugene Delano [III.A] and Susan Magoun (Adams) Delano [III.B]. Second husband of Louisa Millicent Windeatt (Potter) Sheffield, a daughter of Edward Tuckerman Potter and Julia Maria (Blatchford) Potter.
    - Letter from unidentified correspondent, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      In French.
    - Letter from Edwin Martin Watson, 1943 April 8 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      Edwin Martin "Pa" Watson (1883-1945), a senior aide to Franklin Delano Roosevelt, writes to William Adams Delano regarding his son Richard's meeting with the President. The younger Delano invented a method of solar-powered water desalination for use in pilot rescue kits, the "Delano Sunstill," which he had demonstrated to Roosevelt. (The Delanos were distant cousins of the president.)
    - Letter from "Lina", undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Documents Supporting Delano & Aldrich's Argument for Loading Passengers on Planes by Buses at Idlewild Airport (4 copies + map), 1945, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - III.D. William Richard Potter Delano (1909–2000)
    Inventor (see Box 2, Folder 39). Son of William Adams Delano [III.C] and Louisa Millicent Windeatt (Potter) Sheffield Delano.
    - Letter to father, William Adams Delano, 1918 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - III.E. Moreau Delano (1877–1936)
    Banker with Brown Bros. & Co. (now Brown Brothers Harriman & Co.). Son of Eugene Delano [III.A] and Susan Magoun (Adams) Delano [III.B].
    - Letter to mother, Susan Magoun (Adams) Delano, 1901 August 6 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Series IV. Photograph albums, circa 1894-1935
  According to the donor, the photographs in the following albums range in date from 1894 to 1945 (on inspection the documented years appear to cover 1894-1935) and depict the family of Edward Tuckerman Potter and his wife, Julia Blatchford Potter:
  "Edward Tuckerman (Papa) rarely seen except perhaps in Newport RI where he lived at 25 Catherine St. House is shown. Once in Europe. He was from a big family [of] brothers[:] Robert, Nelson, Eliphalet, Henry Codman, William, Howard, Frank, [and] sister Maria[,] who married Launt Thompson[,] the sculptor. No photos. He [Edward Tuckerman Potter] and Julia had eight children[:] Edward, Ethel, Richard, Robert, Julian, Howard, and the youngest[,] Louisa Millicent Windeatt Potter (Sheffield) Delano[,] and Julia Dorothea Cecil Seden (Potter) McIlvaine."
  "Julia Blatchford[,] also known as Mamma[,] and Louisa and Julia Dorothea and their families were the owners of these books and the main subjects. Several years spent in Europe with her two daughters Louisa and Julia Dorothea. The idea was to marry royalty. That did not happen but the photos with Royalty. Much golf and tennis and horseback riding all over Europe. Many travel photos."
  "Louisa Millicent Windeatt Potter (married to Sheffield but I cannot find any photos, he died after one year) known as Louie, LP[,] and LPD. She was married to William Adams Delano[,] who is also known as WAD and Bill. (The principal of Delano & Aldrich.) They were in Europe often and in August of 1914 had to escape in a late night ferry "packed in like the proverbial sardines" from Houlgate [France]. Her son[,] William Richard Potter Delano [was] also known as Dicky. Most photos from the 1930s in Delano albums. They often include the children of Dolly and Tom McIlvaine[,] especially Sandy (Alexander). Also Diana and Dorothea."
  "Dorothea Cecil Selden Potter[,] known as Dolly[,] married to Tompkins McIlvaine[,] also known as Tom or McI. Her children [were] Alexander, Julia Dorothea, [and] Diana."
  "Delano home in Syosset called Muttontown Corners. May pictures of house and gardens and at least one of the stables."
  "WRP Delano[,] i.e., Dicky[,] and his first wife[,] Dorothea Lehmann[,] and their son[,] William[,] also known as Billy. WRPD was an inventor who invented the Delano Sunstill to make fresh water from salt water. Also owned Delano Studios in Setauket."
  "Alexander McIlvaine[,] also known as Sandy. Architect who committed suicide in 1985."
  "Julia Dorothea (Doro) McIlvaine married to Edvard Jorgensen. Also known as Bunty (when a baby[,] after the British play) [or the English-language nursery rhyme, "Bye, baby Bunting"?] and her sister[,] Diana."
  - Photograph album, volume 1, circa 1894-1913 (Box 3)
  - Photograph album, volume 2, circa 1914-1931 (Box 4)
  - Photograph album, volume 3, circa 1929-1935 (Box 2, Folder 44)